mylt.com 2009-09-25

# Life Time Fitness - Feel good inside

| 

**_Life Time Fitness Web Privacy Policy_**  
**Updated Aug 21, 2009** _Information about Life Time Fitness and Our Web Sites_  
Life Time Fitness, Inc. and its subsidiaries ("we” or “Life Time") have established this Web Privacy Policy to explain how we treat information we collect from you through [www.lifetimefitness.com](http://www.lifetimefitness.com/), [www.mylt.com](http://www.mylt.com/), [www.myltwellness.com](http://www.myltwellness.com/) and www.lifelabonline.com, including any sub-domains (“Sites”). This Policy does not apply to personal information collected from you in other ways, including in Life Time centers, or through websites that we do not own or control, including www.lifetimetotalhealth.com. 

We reserve the right to change this Web Privacy Policy at any time, so please review it frequently. If we change this Policy, we will post a revised Policy on our Sites. If you continue to use the Sites thereafter, you hereby provide your consent to the revised Policy. 

**_1\. Collection of Information_**  
We collect information that identifies you as an individual ("personal information") on our Sites. We are the sole owner of the personal information collected on our Sites, unless otherwise prohibited by law. 

_Registration and Account Creation_  
In order to use portions of our Sites, you may be required to register or create an account. To register or create an account, you will be required to provide certain contact information, including your first and last name, date of birth and member ID, and a username and password chosen by you. We will use the email address you provide to send a confirmation email. _Member Interest Groups_  
You may join member interest groups focused on your health or fitness interests through myLT.com. If you join an interest group, we will send emails to you with announcements, updates and information related to your interest areas. _Memberships_ If you purchase a Life Time membership through our Sites, you will be required to provide certain information, including your name, address, birth date, gender, email address, and an emergency contact. You will also be required to provide similar information for other members on your membership. You will be required to provide financial account information. We use this information to establish and manage your membership. We will send you an email confirming your membership. _www.myltwellness.com and www.lifelabonline.com_  
In order to use [www.myltwellness.com](http://www.myltwellness.com/) and [www.lifelabonline.com](http://www.lifelabonline.com/) and their sub-domains, you will be required to register, create an account, agree to our “Screenings Terms and Conditions” and, as applicable, “Disclosure of Information to Employer/Organization,” relating to the services available through these websites. To register and create an account for these websites, you will be required to provide certain contact information, including your first and last name, date of birth, member or other identification number, and a username and password chosen by you. We will use the email address you provide to send a confirmation email, service-related notifications and scheduling confirmations. You may also choose to, but are not required to, enter certain wellness information related to your health on these websites. We will also use your information as described in our “Screenings Terms and Conditions” and, as applicable, “Disclosure of Information to Employer/Organization. _Other Products and Services_  
If you purchase other products or services through our Sites, you will be required to provide certain billing, shipping and financial account information. We will use this information for customer services issues, payment purposes, and to process or fulfill your purchase through a third-party service provider. We may also provide the opportunity to obtain complimentary products or services through the Sites, such as a guest pass. In that event, you will be required to provide certain information, including your name, address, email address, phone number, and age. We will use this information to send you the guest pass or other product or service. _Surveys, Giveaways and Contests_  
We may provide you the opportunity to voluntarily participate in surveys, giveaways or contests on our Sites. If you choose to participate, we may request certain personal information from you, including your name, gender, age, email address, membership status or other information. We will use the information to notify winners as applicable. _Inquiries_  
We provide you the opportunity to voluntarily contact us with inquiries. If you choose to do so, you will be required or requested to provide certain personal information, including your name, phone number, email, and membership status. We will use this information to respond to your inquiry. _Log Files, Cookies, and Clear Gifs_  
We use log files, cookies and clear gifs on our Sites and in our HTML-based emails to track the interests of our users. Log files include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring and exit pages, operating system, date/time stamps, and clickstream data. Cookies are small text files that are stored on a user’s computer for record-keeping purposes, including session ID cookies (which expire when you close your browser) and persistent cookies (which remain on your hard drive for an extended period of time). Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier which are embedded invisibly on web pages. The information stored or contained in log files, cookies and clear gifs does not personally identify individual users. If you remove persistent cookies, you may still use our Sites. _Strategic Partners_  
We sometimes permit other companies to advertise on our Sites, such as our strategic business partners who offer discounts to Life Time members. Our strategic partners may use one or more of the technologies above to measure the effectiveness or personalize the content of their advertisements by tracking user interests. We do not control the use of these technologies, and they are not covered by this Web Privacy Policy. _Children_  
We do not knowingly collect personal information from or solicit persons under 13 years of age. 

**_2\. Use of Information_**

 _Life Time_  
In addition to the uses of information noted above, we will use your personal information for member or customer service purposes, including to respond to your inquiries, to provide the services or products you request, and to manage your relationship with us, including but not limited to communications about changes in monthly dues, fees or center access privileges or collection of past due amounts related to your membership. 

We may also use your personal information to contact you for marketing or informational purposes, including communications to promote products or services offered by Life Time or our strategic partners or to provide information about activities, opportunities, programs, or other items which may be of interest to you as member of Life Time or a particular member interest group. If your information was obtained through [www.myltwellness.com](http://www.myltwellness.com/), www.lifelabonline.com or their sub-domains, then your information will only be used for informational and health management purposes subject to applicable privacy laws and regulations. 

We may also use your personal information for our research and development purposes, such as to improve or personalize your experience on our Sites. This excludes information obtained through [www.myltwellness.com](http://www.myltwellness.com/), www.lifelabonline.com or its sub-domains. 

_Discussion Boards and Forums_  
Any personal information or other user content (e.g., messages, text, files, images, video, photos, sounds or other materials) which you post, submit, transmit, email, message, upload, share, store or otherwise make available on a Discussion Board or Form may be read, collected or used for any purpose by us and other users of the board or forum. We are not responsible for the personal information or other user content you choose to post in these boards or forums. We reserve the right to restrict, disable, suspend or terminate your access to or use of all or any parts of the Sites without prior notice or liability to you. _Third-Party Service Providers/Agents_  
We use other companies to perform certain functions on our behalf and to provide you certain web-based applications, services and resources, including processing payments or fulfilling orders for products or services; processing athletic event registrations; servicing and maintaining our Sites; managing your relationship with us, including sending communications; and assisting you in managing your health and fitness experience. We may also use other companies to conduct research, surveys, giveaways or contests. Unless you consent to it, we do not sell, rent or otherwise provide your personal information to third parties for marketing purposes. _Legal/Law Enforcement_  
We reserve the right to disclose personal information about you as required by law and when we reasonably believe that disclosure is necessary to comply with a court order, a judicial proceeding, public health requirements or legal process. We also reserve the right to disclose personal information to law enforcement officials engaged in legitimate investigations; to prosecute or defend against claims related to Life Time, its Site users, members, guests or employees, including but not limited to enforcement of the terms of the myLT.com Use Agreement or to respond to claims that User Content has been posted in violation of the rights of third parties; or to otherwise reasonably protect the interests, rights, property or safety of Life Time, its Site users, members, guests, employees or the general public. 

**_3\. Your Information Choices_**

 _Accessing and Changing Your Personal Information_  
You may review, correct and update personal information related to your membership with Life Time on myLT.com. _Opting Out of Marketing Communications_  
You may opt out of Life Time’s marketing communications via direct mail, email and/or telephone by changing your Communications Preferences on our Site. 

**_4\. Security_**  
We follow generally-accepted industry standards to protect your personal information. 

_Security Measures_  
When you create an account, we enable you to choose a username, password and security question answer in order to help protect access to the account. You are responsible to maintain the security and integrity of your username, password and security question answers. We encrypt sensitive personal information, such as your financial account information, using secure socket layer technology (SSL). While we use commercially reasonable security measures, no method of internet transmission or electronic storage of personal information is 100% secure and therefore we cannot guarantee its absolute security. _Links to Other Sites_  
The Sites contain links to other websites that we do not own or control. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or content of other sites. When you leave our Sites, we encourage you to review the privacy practices of such sites. 

**_5\. Contact Us_**  
If you have any inquiry or concern about the Sites’ use of your personal information as provided in this Web Privacy Policy, please contact [webmaster@lifetimefitness.com](mailto:%20webmaster@lifetimefitness.com). Life Time Fitness’ corporate office is located at 2902 Corporate Place, Chanhassen, MN, 55317.   
  
---|---
